now let's go back to the unit circle
in the unit circle we said that
it's a circle that has a radius of one
so if we were to draw a triangle
the hypotenuse of the triangle will have
a value of 1 because that's the radius
that's the distance between the center
of the circle and a point on a circle
now this is x and this is y
and on the inside we have the angle
theta
now let's see if that angle corresponds
to an angle of 45 degrees
well actually let's make it 30.
let's say theta is 30.
so that would correspond to a point
of
root 3 over 2 that's the x value and the
y value would be
one
half now we said that sine of theta
when we have a unit circle
and keep in mind this will be true when
r is one if r is not one the equation
will change which we'll talk about later
but for a unit circle
sine theta is simply y
so in this case sine 30 is the y
coordinate one half
cosine theta
we said it's x
now there are some other trigonometric
functions they need to know there's six
of them these are the first two
tangent theta
is sine
divided by cosine
so tangent theta is y divided by x
cosecant theta
is one over y
and secant theta
is one over x
cotangent theta is x divided by y
so those are the six trigonometric
functions
that you need to be aware of